VINEETH SUVARNA PRADEEP

Frontend Developer

Personal Info

Phone

07587925198

E-mail

vineethpradeeps@gmail.com

Location

Swansea, UK

Links

My Journey Portfolio https://vineethjourney.netlify.app

Skills

Programming Languages



Front-End Technologies



Back-End Technologies



Database Management



Testing



Other Skills



I am a passionate and self-driven front-end web application developer and UX/UI designer with 10 years of experience. Demonstrating exceptional attention to detail and extensive knowledge of design principles, I have effectively implemented design concepts into interactive applications and websites. I deliver cutting-edge solutions that enhance user experiences and fulfill client goals. I am fully committed to advancing creativity and technological advancement to produce outstanding results. I am eager to utilize my extensive experience and interdisciplinary skill set to propel innovation, resolve intricate challenges, and contribute significantly to projects and teams in this ever-evolving industry.

Experience

Senior Application Developer

IBM India Private Limited

08/2022 - 10/2023

- Developed and implemented a new front-end architecture using React.js.
- Developed menus, call flows, route methods, and prompts, configured and customized them using Amazon Connect instances.
- Linked IVR incoming and outgoing call center data to the React application widget using AWS services and implemented a custom CCP.

Tech Lead - UI Developer

HCL Technologies

05/2020 - 08/2022

- Designed and developed a reusable component library using the BEM methodology, reducing development time by 40%.
- Developed a serverless mock API for client front-end experiences using Mirage Js.
- Improved webpage load times and resolved performance and scalability issues.
- Utilized Redux for state management, reducing code complexity by 25% and increasing team productivity by 15%.
- Implemented automated testing platforms and unit tests, increasing overall code coverage from 85% to 100%.

Senior Analyst - UI Developer

Apptium Technology India Pvt. Ltd

03/2018 - 01/2020

- Led the successful development of three major Angular web application projects.
- Integrated third-party services and APIs to enhance functionalities, increasing user interaction.
- Developed a new Angular-based dashboard for a client.
- Created comprehensive unit tests and e2e test suites, improving overall code quality by 15% and reducing delays caused by bugs by 90%.

Business Associate

Crown Solution India Pvt Ltd

06/2017 - 11/2017

- Collaborated with designers and stakeholders to create a user-friendly interface application.
- Developed and maintained RESTful APIs, enabling seamless communication between web applications and third-party services.
- Debugged and troubleshot web applications, reducing bug-related delays by 20% and increasing overall code quality by 15%.

Software Web Designer

DUCEN IT Pvt Ltd 10/2013 - 06/2017

- Developed and maintained a complex user interface for a web application.
- Collaborated with product managers and designers to create acomprehensive UI style guide.
- Utilized cutting-edge CSS3 concepts to create user-friendly, responsivedesigns.
- · Implemented accessibility standards and guidelines.
- Created and maintained technical documentation, ensuring seamlessknowledge transfer and collaboration.
- Facilitated a smooth MVP release by coordinating efforts between UI/UXdesigners and back-end developers.

System Administrator

Narayanaguru College of Engineering

11/2007 - 05/2010

- Developed visual design concepts, enhancing website traffic and conversion rates using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Created storyboards and animation graphics for various digital products.
- Designed user interfaces, experiences, and wireframes to meet customerneeds.
- Produced marketing materials such as flyers, posters, and digitaladvertisements.

Career Achievements

- Appreciation was given to the multi-user customisable theme that was built for the BI Tool.
- Product tools from the developer's coding perspective. A quick coding snippet was implemented
- The concept visualisation award is for best performer appreciation

Education

Master's degree

Nehru Arts and Science College
Electronics and Communication System

2012
3 GPA

Diploma

Image Education Institute 2007
Digital Visual Media - Animation 3.5 GPA

Bachelor's degree

Malankara Catholic College 2005 Physics 2 GPA

Hobbies & Interests

Cricket, Gym, Learning languages, Photography.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Swansea VINEETH PRADEEP

Date: